Guide to the Francis M. Finch papers, 1851-1889.
Finch, Francis M. papers, 1851-1889
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Francis M. Finch papers, 1851-1889.
433
Francis M.(Francis Miles), Finch 1827-1907.
6.8 cubic ft., 1 mapcase folder
Correspondence, legal documents, certificates, manuscripts, account books
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Legal and business documents and correspondence of Walbridge and Finch, Boardman and Finch, and Francis M. Finch; also, correspondence and accounts of the Finch family, including letters from Daniel Coit Gilman, Chauncey M. Depew, Hiram S. Sage, and others dealing with legal, personal, literary, and educational subjects. Trial testimony, instructions to the jury, and other material pertaining to the Edward H. Rulloff murder case. Also, gold Venetian ceremonial cufflink-coins presented to Finch by Andrew Dickson White; poetry, material pertaining to Cornell University Library, and diplomas. Francis M. Finch's handwritten dedication of the Ezra Cornell Library in downtown Ithaca, December 20, 1866, and his presentation of Jennie McGraw's chimes to the University on October 7, 1868. Songs, poems, and photographs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Legal and business documents and correspondence of Walbridge and Finch, Boardman and Finch, and Francis M. Finch; also, correspondence and accounts of the Finch family, including letters from Daniel Coit Gilman, Chauncey M. Depew, Hiram S. Sage, and others dealing with legal, personal, literary, and educational subjects. Trial testimony, instructions to the jury, and other material pertaining to the Edward H. Rulloff murder case. Also, gold Venetian ceremonial cufflink-coins presented to Finch by Andrew Dickson White; poetry, material pertaining to Cornell University Library, and diplomas.
Francis M. Finch's handwritten dedication of the Ezra Cornell Library in downtown Ithaca, December 20, 1866, and his presentation of Jennie McGraw's chimes to the University on October 7, 1868.
Original manuscript of poem, "The Songs of the Guns for The Society of the Army of the Potomac, June 17, 1879," 31 pages handwritten in ink with notations in pencil in a bound notebook. Black-and-white photograph of Francis Miles Finch as a jurist, ca. 1890; large black-and-white photograph of Miles Francis Finch, son of Francis Miles Finch, aged 9, ca. 1872; framed copy of Finch's poem, "The Blue and the Gray," September 1867.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Finch, Francis M.1827-1907.; Depew, Chauncey M.; Finch Family.; Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908.; Rulloff, Edward M.; Sage, Hiram S.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Boardman and Finch.; Walbridge and Finch.
Subjects:
Trials (Murdeer)--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Family--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Legal professions--New York (State); Lawyers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1814-1841 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1852-1854 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1855-1856 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1860-1869 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1862-1866 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1867-1869 (Box 6)
- Volume, 1869-1873 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1870-1873 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1872-1874 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1875-1876 (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1877-1904 (Box 10)
- Undated Writings and Manuscripts (Box 11)
- Undated Writings and Manuscripts (Box 12)
- Legal briefs (loose mss.), no date (Box 13)
- 7 volumes: Legal log book, 1880-1895 (Box 14)
- Volumes of writings, 1906 (Box 14)
- Mss.: Chapter 10 Moses and Menu (loose pp.) (Box 15)
- Volume: The Scenery of Ithaca (Box 15)
- Account book. desc. add., 1871-1878 (Box 16)
- Account book (3 vols.), 1850-1875 (Box 16)
- 1 volume minutes of Supreme Court Case People of State of New york vs. Elizabeth Higgin, April 10, 1865 (Box 16)
- Transcript of lectures for History and Evolution of Law, with synopsis, ca. 1898-1904 (Box 17)
- Eqyptian scarab stick pin given by Andrew Dickson White to Francis Miles Finch, no date; MU-2024 (Box 18)
- Two gold Venetian ceremonial cufflink-coins (Ducato of Venice), 1700's; MU-2025 (Box 18)
  -coins depict Doge Alois Mocenigo II (1700-1709) and Doge Ludovico Manin (1789-1797)
- Finch's handwritten dedication of the Ezra Cornell Library and presentation of the McGraw chimes, 1866, 1868 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Poems, no date (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Poems, no date (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Printed poems, 1849-1900 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Songs, no date (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1844-1905 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Copies of letters from Ezra Cornell, ca. 1963-1865 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Transcripts - "The Blue and the Grey", 1867 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- "The Songs of the Guns, for the Society of the Army of the Potomac", 1879 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Edward Rulloff trial materials (Folder MSS Box 3, 433m)
- Certificates, Awards, and Diplomas for Francis Finch (Folder 1)